// Computer Science and Information Technology
let questions = [
    {
   numb: 1,
   question: "Which of the following is the first calculating device?",
   answer: "Abacus",
   options: [
     "Calculator",
     "Abacus",
     "Turing Machine",
     "Pascaline"
   ]
 },
    {
   numb: 2,
   question: "Who among the following considered as the 'father of artificial intelligence'?",
   answer: "John McCarthy",
   options: [
     "JP Eckert",
     "John McCarthy",
     "Lee De Forest",
     "Charles Babbage"
   ]
 },
    {
   numb: 3,
   question: "Which was the world's first successful electronic computer?",
   answer: "ENIAC electronic Numerical Integrator and computer",
   options: [
     "PARAM",
     "CRAY-1",
     "Pascaline",
     "ENIAC electronic Numerical Integrator and computer"
   ]
 },
   {
   numb: 4,
   question: "Which was first virus detected on ARPANET, the forerunner of the internet in the early 1970s?",
   answer: "Creeper Virus",
   options: [
     "Exe Flie",
     "Creeper Virus",
     "Peeper Virus",
     "Trozen horse"
   ]
 },
   {
   numb: 5,
   question: "Find out the correct definition of Wide Area Network (WAN)",
   answer: "A computer network that covers a broad area.",
   options: [
     "It is a programming language with strong abstraction from the details of the computer.",
     "It is a collection of computers interconnected with each other through cables to share their data, information and other common hardware resources.",
     "A computer network that covers a broad area.",
     "A  computer network covering a small physical area like a home, office or small groups of buildings, such as a school or an airport."
   ]
 },
   {
   numb: 6,
   question: "Select the example of application software of computer:",
   answer: "Both A and B",
   options: [
     "Ms Word",
     "Ms Excel",
     "Both A and B",
     "MS-DOS"
   ]
 },
   {
   numb: 7,
   question: "Which of the following is also called translator?",
   answer: "Language Processor",
   options: [
     "Data representation",
     "MS-DOS",
     "Operating System",
     "Language Processor"
   ]
 },
  {
   numb: 8,
   question: "How the quality of printer is measured?",
   answer: "Dots per Inch",
   options: [
     "Alphabet per strike",
     "Words per Inch",
     "Strike per Inch",
     "Dots per Inch"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 9,
   question: "What does the command prompt uses?",
   answer: "CLI (Command Line Interface)",
   options: [
     "CLI (Command Line Interface)",
     "GUI (Graphical User Interface)",
     "Text User Interface TUI",
     "None of the above"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 10,
   question: "Which out of the following helps in quickly help you rename a file or folder?",
   answer: "F2",
   options: [
     "F3",
     "F8",
     "F9",
     "F2"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 11,
   question: "Which out the following is a scripting language?",
   answer: "All of the above",
   options: [
     "Java",
     "Python",
     "Lisp",
     "All of the above"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 12,
   question: "What is the full of form ALU?",
   answer: "Arithmetic Logic Unit",
   options: [
     "Analyst Logic Unit",
     "Algebraic Logic Unit",
     "Arithmetic Logic Unit",
     "None of the above"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 13,
   question: "Which out of the following can be called as modifiers?",
   answer: "Keys Alt, Shift, or Ctrl",
   options: [
     "Keys Alt, Shift, or Ctrl",
     "Keys Tab, caps lock , End",
     "Keys, Page Up , Page Down, Print SC",
     "Keys Num Lock, Backspace, and Tab"
   ]
 },

 {
   numb: 14,
   question: "How many way are there to carry out floating-point operation?",
   answer: "1",
   options: [
     "3",
     "1",
     "2",
     "4"
   ]
 },
 {
   numb: 15,
   question: "Who invented mechanical calculator called Pascaline?",
   answer: "Blaise Pascal",
   options: [
     "Charles Babbage",
     "Alan Turing",
     "Blaise Pascal",
     "None to the above"
   ]
 },
];